<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Gati Aher</title>
    <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Gati Aher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:21:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures for Large Scale Information Retrieval</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/data-structures-for-large-scale-information-retrieval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:21:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/data-structures-for-large-scale-information-retrieval/</guid>
      <description>5-minute video overview:    1 INTRODUCTION 2 BACKGROUND INFORMATION  2.1 Inverted Indexes For Fast (Constant Time) Lookup 2.2 Big Document IDs Use a Lot of Space 2.3 An Overview of Compression Codes: Balancing Space Savings and Time Cost   3 ELIAS-FANO COMPRESSION  3.1 Introducing Quasi-Succinct Elias-Fano: Fast, Small and Better than Sequential Decoding 3.2 Speed-Up Elias-Fano with Quantum Skipping 3.3 Review of Elias-Fano   4 PARTITIONED ELIAS-FANO COMPRESSION  4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eigenfaces and Out of Distribution Data</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/eigenfaces-and-out-of-distribution-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 13:12:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/eigenfaces-and-out-of-distribution-data/</guid>
      <description>Facial Recognition Dataset Facial Recognition Via Nearest Neighbor Distance Room for Improvement PCA Toy Example Delving into the Details of the Facial Recognition Pipeline  Step 1. Standardize Dataset Step 2. Compute Sample Covariance Matrix from Standardized Train Dataset Step 3. Compute Eigenvectors and Eigenvalues of the Covariance Matrix Step 4. Pick k Eigenvectors Step 5. Project and Reconstruct Dataset onto k Eigenvectors Step 6. Evaluation   Applications Further Reading:  Facial Recognition Through this project, I wanted to learn more about the technique of Principal Component Analysis (PCA), namely how to reason about the result of applying PCA on a dataset, and the effects of testing on out-of-distribution data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral Analysis of Bacteria S-Layer</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/spectral-analysis-of-bacteria-s-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 22:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/spectral-analysis-of-bacteria-s-layer/</guid>
      <description>Background Info: Bacteria S-Layers Introducing Hot Peanuts FFT In Python Code Step 1. Remove Vertical and Horizontal Pattern Noise Step 2. Identify Key Periodic Frequencies Step 3. Calculate Size and Scale Step 4. Identify Shape Extra Credit: Visualize the S-Layer Units Conclusion  Background Info: Bacteria S-Layers Most prokaryotic cells are encapsulated by a surface layer (S-layer) consisting of repeating units of S-layer proteins. These S-layers protect cells from the outside, provide mechanical stability, and play roles in spreading disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1D and 2D Fourier Transforms</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/1d-and-2d-fourier-transforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 14:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/1d-and-2d-fourier-transforms/</guid>
      <description>Fourier Transforms: A Pattern-Based Perspective 1D Fourier Transforms  Understanding the 1D Math  The DFT-matrix (W) Post Projection Processing   Read the 1D Frequency Plots   Generalizing to 2D Fourier Transform  Understand the 2D Math Read the 2D Plots   Exercises Further Reading  Fourier Transforms: A Pattern-Based Perspective In the 1800s, Joseph Fourier showed that periodic functions could be written as an infinite sum of sinusoids.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>