<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gati Aher&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gati Aher&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 10:18:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://GatiAher.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments in Handwriting Detection With Faster R-CNN</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/experiments-in-handwriting-detection-with-faster-r-cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 10:43:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/experiments-in-handwriting-detection-with-faster-r-cnn/</guid>
      <description>1 INTRODUCTION  1.1 Datasets 1.2 Tough-to-Beat Baseline Model   2 BACKGROUND INFORMATION  2.1 Overview of Detectron-v2&amp;rsquo;s Faster R-CNN with FPN - DataMapper - Backbone Network - Details on Feature Pyramid Network - Region Proposal Network (RPN) - RPN Head - Map Ground Truths to Feature Maps With Cell Anchors (during training) - Loss Function (during training) - Box Proposal Selection - ROI Head - Re-Sampling and Matching (during training) - Cropping - Box Head - Loss Calculation - Inference 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 10:18:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a software engineering student at Olin College of Engineering in Needham, MA. I am most passionate about data analysis, machine learning, natural language processing, computer vision.
If you are curious about my professional experience, see my CV.
Contact  Email: gativaher@gmail.com Github: @GatiAher LinkedIn: gatiaher  Fun fact: Gati means velocity in Sanskrit. My full name, Gati Vikas Aher, roughly translates to the definition of instantaneous velocity (via a bilingual pun).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures for Large Scale Information Retrieval</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/data-structures-for-large-scale-information-retrieval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 21:21:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/data-structures-for-large-scale-information-retrieval/</guid>
      <description>5-minute video overview:    1 INTRODUCTION 2 BACKGROUND INFORMATION  2.1 Inverted Indexes For Fast (Constant Time) Lookup 2.2 Big Document IDs Use a Lot of Space 2.3 An Overview of Compression Codes: Balancing Space Savings and Time Cost   3 ELIAS-FANO COMPRESSION  3.1 Introducing Quasi-Succinct Elias-Fano: Fast, Small and Better than Sequential Decoding 3.2 Speed-Up Elias-Fano with Quantum Skipping 3.3 Review of Elias-Fano   4 PARTITIONED ELIAS-FANO COMPRESSION  4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bloom for Search From Scratch</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/bloom-for-search-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 09:35:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/bloom-for-search-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>1 PROJECT GOALS AND RESULTS 2 BLOOM FILTERS  2.1 Demo 1: Bloom filter to spellcheck a query 2.2 Demo 2: Bloom filter to spellcheck a file   3 BIT-SLICED DOCUMENT SIGNATURES  3.1 Demo 3: Information retrieval on xkcd comics transcripts   4 APPENDIX  4.1 Note on Code Design  4.1.1 Bit-wise functions that take advantage of powers of 2 4.1.2 Function pointers for cleaner, reusable code 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eigenfaces and Out of Distribution Data</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/eigenfaces-and-out-of-distribution-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:12:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/eigenfaces-and-out-of-distribution-data/</guid>
      <description>1 INTRODUCTION  Dataset   2 FACIAL RECOGNITION WITH NEAREST NEIGHBOR DISTANCE  Room for Improvement  PCA Toy Example     3 FACIAL RECOGNITION WITH PCA NEAREST NEIGHBOR DISTANCE  Step 1. Standardize Dataset Step 2. Compute Sample Covariance Matrix from Standardized Train Dataset Step 3. Compute Eigenvectors and Eigenvalues of the Covariance Matrix Step 4. Pick k Eigenvectors Step 5. Project and Reconstruct Dataset onto k Eigenvectors Step 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectral Analysis of Bacteria S-Layer</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/spectral-analysis-of-bacteria-s-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 22:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/spectral-analysis-of-bacteria-s-layer/</guid>
      <description>1 INTRODUCTION 2 BACKGROUND INFORMATION  Bacteria S-Layers FFT In Python Code   3 APPLYING, CLEANING, AND INTERPRETING THE 2D FFT  Step 1. Remove Vertical and Horizontal Pattern Noise Step 2. Identify Key Periodic Frequencies Step 3. Calculate Size and Scale Step 4. Identify Shape Bonus: Visualize the S-Layer Units   4 CONCLUSION  1 INTRODUCTION In 2015-2016, Professor Jean Huang and her research group cultured a phototrophic bacteria from the Little Sippewissett Salt Marsh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1D and 2D Fourier Transforms</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/1d-and-2d-fourier-transforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 14:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/1d-and-2d-fourier-transforms/</guid>
      <description>1 INTRODUCTION 2 1D FOURIER TRANSFORM  Understanding the 1D Math  The DFT-matrix (W) Post Projection Processing   Read the 1D Frequency Plots   3 GENERALIZING TO 2D FOURIER TRANSFORM  Understand the 2D Math Read the 2D Plots Exercises   4 FURTHER READING  1 INTRODUCTION In the 1800s, Joseph Fourier showed that periodic functions could be written as an infinite sum of sinusoids. His theory paved the way for Fourier Analysis, a useful tool for signal and data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>