<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Olin Microbiology Lab (Undergraduate Research) on Gati Aher</title>
    <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/tags/olin-microbiology-lab-undergraduate-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Olin Microbiology Lab (Undergraduate Research) on Gati Aher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:12:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://GatiAher.github.io/tags/olin-microbiology-lab-undergraduate-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Facial Recognition Using Principal Component Analysis</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/facial-recognition-using-principal-component-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 13:12:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/facial-recognition-using-principal-component-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have used multiple variations of Principal Component Analysis (PCA) in my research on microbial community analysis. To explain the core theory and assumptions of PCA to my lab group, I fleshed out an analysis of a toy example (eigenfaces) that I had originally seen in class. This analysis reasons about the assumptions of PCA and the effects of applying it to out-of-distribution data by using PCA to perform facial recognition on a dataset of my classmates&amp;rsquo; faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was invited to present this project at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ms-my.facebook.com/MathUpConference/photos/because-the-mathup-conference-is-conducted-in-both-polish-and-english-another-du/2805409529774282&#34;&gt;Łódź University&amp;rsquo;s SP2021 [virtual] MathUp conference&lt;/a&gt; at Łódź University, Poland. The conference was an incredibly fun opportunity to meet fellow researchers and data scientists!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fourier Transform Detective Story!</title>
      <link>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/a-fourier-transform-detective-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 22:24:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://GatiAher.github.io/projects/a-fourier-transform-detective-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A group of research students had tried to use a 2D discrete Fourier Transform to characterize the pattern of repeating protein units on a bacteria surface layer image. Since their spectral graph looked unusually messy and their pattern estimates seemed very wrong, my research professor asked me to take a crack at interpreting and cleaning it. This was a neat application of understanding the mathematical assumptions of a technique to properly isolate and interpret results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
